www.tvsubtitles.net
형법 체계에 있어
성관련 범죄는
In the criminal justice system,
특히 극악무도한 것으로 여겨진다
sexually based offenses are
considered especially heinous.
뉴욕에는 성범죄 사건을
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
전담하는 형사들이 있고
who investigate
these vicious felonies
그들을 S.V.U.라고 한다
are members of an elite squad
known as
the Special Victims Unit.
이건 그들의 이야기다
These are their stories.
테사, 테사
Tessa. Tessa.
아가, 이리 와
Sweetie, come here.
널 잡아야겠다!
I'm gonna get you!
Awoo!
Whoo!
선크림 너무 바르는거 아니야?
우리가 싫어하던
What's with the sunscreen?
You're turning into one of those
극성 엄마처럼 되어가고 있네
women we used to make fun of.
당신 피부가 창백하잖아
화상 입으면 어떡해
She's got your fair skin.
She'll burn.
And what do you think?
- 봐, 저게 뭐지?
- 테사, 봐, 오!
- Look, what's that?
- Tessa, look. Oh!
오! 오, 예?
Oh! Oh, yeah?
어디 가려고?
Oh, where you going?
놀고 싶어?
가서 놀고 싶어?
Do you want to play?
Do you want to come play?
못 본 이메일이 수십개는 있어
교대 좀 해줄래?
I'm two dozen emails behind.
Can you take the first shift?
알겠어, 근데
빨리 해, 알겠지?
Okay, sure, but listen,
be quick, okay?
내가 애 보러 나온줄 알잖아
It's like they know
I'm on kid duty.
좋아, 가서 놀자
Okay. Let's go play.
- 노는거, 놀자
- 가서 놀자
- Play, yeah. Play.
- Let's go play.
- 놀아? 놀아?
- 그래, 가서 놀자
- Play? Play?
- Yeah, go play.
엄마
Mama.
엄마 엄마
Ma mama.
나 지금 놀이터니까
크고 빠르게 말해줘요
I'm at the playground.
Talk loud and fast.
가장 일 잘하는 영업사원이 파워포인트에
My best salesman
had the wrong data
잘못된 데이터를 집어 넣었어
for his powerpoint.
- 도와주려고?
- 그 사람들은 멍청해
- You bail him out?
- Oh, they're idiots.
- 심지어 틀렸다는 것도--
- 테사 어딨어?
- They can't even--
- Where's Tessa?
- 모래에서 놀고 있지
- 테사!
- She's playing in the sand.
- Tessa!
테사!
테사?
Tessa!
Tessa?
여기 있었는데
Okay, she was right here.
테사!
Tessa!
아가, 아가
테사?
Hey, hey.
Tessa?
테사!
Tessa!
- 테사!
- Tessa!
- 테사! 테사! 테사!
- 테사! 테사!
- Tessa! Tessa! Tessa!
- Tessa! Tessa!
괜찮으세요?
Are you okay, honey?
조지, 조금만--
조금만 진정해보세요
Josie, I need you to--
I need you to stay calm,
숨쉬려고 노력하시구요, 아시겠죠?
now try to breathe, okay?
- 제가 하고 싶은 말은, 애가--
- 잘하고 있어요
- Look, I'm telling you, she--
- There you go.
모래에서 놀고 있었고
She was playing
in the sand.
전화를 한 뒤 봤을 땐
애가 없어져있었어요
I took a call, I looked up,
she was gone.
- 전화는 얼마동안 했죠?
- 모르겠어요
- What time was the call?
- I don't know.
전화기에 있을텐데요
Well, it'll be on your cell.
좋아요, 숨을 쉬면서
얘기 해주세요
That's good.
Take a breath, and tell me,
- 테사가 뭘 입고 있었죠?
- 분홍색 바지요
- what was Tessa wearing?
- Pink pants.
- 분홍색 자켓두요
- 네
- A pink jacket.
- Okay.
오늘 아침에 찍은거에요
This is from earlier
this morning.
아, 잠시, 잠시만요
Oh, wait, wait, hold up.
누구죠?
Who's that?
오늘 공원에서 이 사람 봤어요?
See this guy
in the park today?
아니요
- No.
- Un-uh.
한살짜리 여자애고
금발에, 분홍색 옷이에요
One-year-old girl,
blond hair, pink outfit?
실례합니다, 부인
- Mm-mm.
- Excuse me, ma'am.
놀이터에서 이 남자를 보셨나요?
You see this man
at the playground?
오늘은 못 봤는데
전에도 여기 온 적 있어요
Not today,
but he's been here before.
애가 있지도 않았구요
저 사람이 리스트에 있다더군요
He's not a parent.
They say he's on the list.
사진을 찍어서 그 사람을 봤을 때
경찰서에 신고를 했어요
I take his picture and I call
the precinct when I see him.
여기요
There.
- 알렌 클라이드?
- 경찰이다
- Allen Clyde?
- Police.
- 문제 일으키지 말아주세요
- 애는 어딨어?
- I don't want trouble.
- Where is she?
여기 애기 있지, 알렌?
You got a little girl in here,
Allen?
- 전 아무 짓도 안했어요
- 없다고?
- I didn't do anything.
- No?
당신은 성범죄자고
놀이터에 있었어
You're a sex offender
and you were at the playground.
아침에 거기서 뭐 했던거야?
What were you doing there
this morning?
전 밤에 잡역부로 일 해요
I work the night shift
as a janitor.
그냥 공원을 지나간 것 뿐이에요
I was just cutting through
the park.
이 애한테 말도 좀 걸고?
Talk to this little girl?
그냥 내려주려고 한거에요
I just wanted
to help her down.
- 애가 무서워 해서요
- 이 애 어딨어?
- She was scared.
- Where is she?
몰라요
걔 엄마가 데려갔어요
I don't know.
Her mother took her.
다른 변명 없어?
애 엄마가 애가 어딨는지 모르는데
Try again, the mother
doesn't know where she is.
아뇨, 아니에요, 거짓말 아니에요!
애 엄마가 데려갔어요
No, no, I'm not lying!
She left with her mom.
그래? 애 엄마가 어떻게 생겼는데?
Yeah? What did
the mother look like?
어, 스트레이트 금발 머리에
시스루 같은 옷을 입고 있었어요
Uh, straight blond hair,
see-through dress with, like,
검은색 패턴이 있었구요
a black pattern on it.
그 여자가 애를 데려갔어요
가서 찾아보세요!
She's got that baby.
Go find her!
알렌, 당신은 그 놀이터에
있었으면 안되거든
Allen, you weren't supposed
to be in that playground.
가시지!
Let's go!
2012년 11월 14일 방영
14시즌 7편 Vanity's Bonfire
마리스카 하지테이
(올리비아 벤슨 역)
대니 피노
(닉 아마로 역)
켈리 기디쉬
(아만다 롤링 역)
리차드 벨저
(존 먼치 역)
아이스 티
(오다핀 '핀' 투투올라 역)
댄 플로렉
(도날드 크레이건 역)
LAW&
ORDER
SPECIAL VICTIMS UNIT
번역 by 내가아는카페 날로
blog.naver.com/narlo
Sync & corrections by Alex1969
www.addic7ed.com
놀이터에서 데려온 성범죄자가
여기서 잠이 든다고?
The sex offender from the
playground falls asleep here?
- 좋은 신호는 아닌데
- 마리화나 폈을 수도 있죠
- Not a good sign.
- Could be the joint he smoked.
밤 근무 하고 나서
긴장풀려고 말이죠
Allen was winding down
from a night shift.
공원에 있던 다른 사람 말로는
저 남자를 알고 있대요
The other mothers in the park
said that they know this guy.
그 근처를 돌아다니며
주시하고 다닌다구요
They said that he hangs around
and he watches.
테사는 저 남자 아파트에 없어요
주위도 뒤져봤구요
Tessa wasn't in his apartment.
We checked the surrounding area.
어딘가 숨겨둘 시간도 없었구요
He didn't have a lot of time
to stash her.
좋아, 깨워
오늘 아침에 대해서 조사하고
Okay, wake him up,
make him go over his morning.
저 남자가 본 테사를 데려갔다는 엄마,
자세한 사항까지 물어
This mother he saw take Tessa?
Every detail.
아빠가 찍었다는 비디오는
테사에게 선크림 바르는 영상이에요
The dad videotaped Tessa
getting sunscreen put on.
이게 요즘 부모들이 하는 거에요?
I mean, is that
what parents do now?
전부 다 녹화해놓는거?
Just record everything?
한순간이라도 놓치지 않고 싶은거지
Well, you don't want
to miss a moment.
만약 저희 엄마가 부활절에 월마트에 데려가고,
If my mother took me to
Walmart for the Easter photo
산타클로스 보러 몰에 데려갔으면
and to the mall
for the one with Santa,
제 동생이 나타났겠어요?
by the time
my sister came around?
아무도 그런걸로
귀찮게 하진 않는다구요
No one even bothered
with that.
저기 그 놈이 있네
SOR : Sex Offender Regisrty
Mm.
Look, there's our SOR.
알렌은 금발 여자가
아이를 데려간걸 봤다고 했어요
Allen claims he saw
a blond woman take her.
저긴 금발인 엄마가 많은데
Well, there's lots
of blond moms.
꽃무늬 드레스를 봐요
Mm, you know,
look for one in a floral dress.
- 이 여자처럼요?
- 네
- Like her?
- Yeah.
잠깐, 저 기저귀 가방
테사의 엄마거랑 같지 않아요?
Hang on, isn't that the same
diaper bag that Tessa's mom has?
저건 아이 아빠의
아기 캐리어에요
And that's
the dad's baby carrier.
알렌이 진실을 얘기한걸까요?
So, Allen could be
telling the truth?
저 사람이 아이를 몰래 데리고
No one looks twice at a mom
leaving the park with a baby
- 공원을 나가는 걸 본 사람은 없어요
- 맞아요
- in her sling.
- Yeah.
좋아요, 반장님께 연락할게요
Okay, I'll go tell Captain.
시내에는 CCTV가
어디든 있으니까요
Downtown there's video
surveillance everywhere.
하나도 빠짐없이 조사해야죠
We gotta go back over
every single one of them.
이건 테사에요
이 여잔 누구죠?
That's Tessa.
Who's that woman?
그걸 알아내려고 하고 있어요
Well, we're trying
to figure that out.
머레이 가의 보안 카메라에서 발견한거에요
We got this from a security
camera on Murray Street.
그럼 이 얼굴을..
Now, you're sure...
전에는 본 적이 없으세요?
that you've
never seen her before?
아뇨, 놀이터에 있는
엄마도 아니에요
No, no,
she's not one of the moms.
이 여자는 누구죠?
왜 이런 짓을 하는거죠?
Who is she?
Why would she do this?
가끔 아이를 납치하는 여자들은
Well, sometimes when a woman
takes a baby, it's because she's
아이와의 관계에 대해서 공상을 가지고 있어요
fantasized a relationship
with the child.
자주 가족들을 훔쳐봐요
Oftentimes,
they've watched the family.
근처에 있었다면
제가 알아봤을거에요
I would have noticed her
hanging around.
직장은 여기서 머나요?
Your job, does it ever
take you out of town?
남편과 아이만 놔두고
떠나신 적 있나요?
Do you ever leave Tessa here
with your husband?
조지는 일 때문에 여행을 가곤 해요
무슨 말이세요?
Yes, Josie travels for work.
What are you saying?
보세요, 브레이든 씨
저희는 그냥 따님을 찾고 싶어요
Now look, Braydon, we just
want to find your daughter.
집에 다른 여자를 들인 적은 없어요
I would never bring
another woman home.
집에 들어올 수 있는
다른 사람은 없나요?
Anyone else have access
to your place?
테사의 유모가 평일에 와요
Uh, Tessa's nanny
is with her on weekdays.
카르멘 실바고, 과테말라 사람인데
Carmen Silva.
She's Guatemalan, but she's been
여기 있은지 십년은 됐어요
here for ten years.
그 분 주소가 필요해요
Okay, I'm gonna need
her address.
주소, 전화번호, 여권 복사본
그거 다 갖고 있어요
Address, phone number, copy of
her passport, I have all of it.
아, 안돼요, 테사를요?
누가 데려간거에요?
Oh, no, little Tessa?
Who would take her?
저희가 알아내려는게 그거에요
Well, that's what we're
trying to find out.
여기에 또 누가 살죠?
Who else lives here?
어, 할머니랑, 어머니랑
어머니 동생이랑, 제 사촌이요
Uh, mi abuelita, mi mama,
her sisters, my cousins.
테사를 12시간 돌보시잖아요
Well, you watch Tessa
12 hours a day.
아이를 보는데 도와준 사람은 없나요?
Anybody ever help you
with her?
다른 사람이랑 함께 두고
떠난 적은 있나요?
Or, you leave her alone
with somebody?
아뇨, 아니에요
전 테사를 항상 곁에 둬요
Oh, no, no, I keep Tessa
always with me.
전 아이를 맥도날드도 안 데려가고
I never take her to McDonald's.
집 안에 사람을 들인 적도 없어요
I never let anyone
in the house.
이 여자 본 적 있나요?
Have you ever seen this woman?
네, 이 여자는 공원에 있는 아이들의
Yes. She's the one
사진을 찍는 사람이에요
who takes the pictures
in the park of the babies.
- 이름은 아세요?
- 아니요
- You know her name?
- No.
근데 어머니의 날에
어머니의 날 : 5월 2번 째 일요일)
But for mother's day,
she gave me
저랑 테사를 찍은 사진을 줬어요
a picture she took
of me and Tessa.
사진을 보관하려고
사진틀을 샀거든요
I bought a frame
to keep it nice.
"Lifemomentsbydia.com."
디아 노빌레의 로프트
반담 거리 245번지
10월 7일, 일요일
문 열어요
Open it up.
실종된 애가 있어요
문 열어줘요
There's a missing baby.
Open it up.
- 디아 노빌레 씨?
- 여기서 뭐하시는겁니까?
- Dia Nobile?
- What are you doing here?
경찰입니다
Police.
디아, 아이를 엄마와 아빠에게
다시 데려다주려고 왔어요
Dia, we need to get that baby
back to her mom and dad.
괜찮아요, 제가 엄마에요
It's okay, I'm her mom.
아이를 정말 잘 보고 계시네요
You're taking good care
of her.
당연하죠
제가 엄마인걸요
Of course I am.
She's mine.
그럼 이 일을 바로 잡을 때까지
So then, I know that you're
gonna want to keep her safe
아이가 안전하길
원하는 것도 알아요, 그렇죠?
until we get all of this
straightened out, right?
- 도와주실건가요?
- 그럼요, 디아
- You would help me with that?
- Absolutely, Dia.
저도 딸이 하나 있어요
이해해요
You know, I have a daughter.
I get it.
지금 상황에서
가장 최선익너요, 디아
So the best thing right now,
Dia,
저에게 아이를 주는거에요
is for you to let me hold her,
okay?
알겠어요, 그냥--
조심하게 데려가세요
Okay, just--
please, be careful.
안녕, 아가
Hey, sweetie.
이리오렴, 아가, 그렇지
Come here, sweetheart, yeah.
괜찮단다, 아가
괜찮아
It's okay, lovie.
It's okay.
안돼요, 하지마요!
No, stop!
아뇨, 그 애는 제 아기에요
제 아이라구요!
No, she's my baby!
She's mine!
디아 노빌레, 당신은 체포되었습니다
Dia Nobile,
you're under arrest.
절 체포하실 순 없어요
전 저 애 엄마인걸요
You can't arrest me.
I'm her mother.
우리가 함께한 모든 것을
폴더에 끼워놨어요
I put everything together
in a folder.
서랍장에 있어요
한번 보세요
It's on the dresser.
Just look at it.
볼거에요, 볼거에요
I will. We will.
다 거기에 있어요
It's all there.
출생 증명서도 있어요
제가 엄마란걸 증명해줄거에요
Her birth certificate.
It proves that I'm her mother.
- 제발요, 제발
- 괜찮아, 아가
- Please, please.
- It's okay, sweetie.
- 엄마, 엄마 보고싶어!
- 알아, 알아 아가
- Mommy. I want mommy!
- I know. I know, lovie.
의사 말로는 신체적으론
아이는 괜찮대요
The doctors say that
physically she's fine.
- 안 다쳤답니다
- 괜찮아, 아가
- She's unhurt.
- You're okay, baby.
어떻게 감사를 표현해야 할지
We can't thank you enough.
아이를 집에 데려갈게요
We'll be taking her home now.
네, 그냥 몇 가지만
좀 정리하면 됩니다
Yeah, we just need
to clear up a few things.
뭘 정리 한단 얘기죠?
What else is there
to clear up?
테사를 데려간 여자인 디아 노블레의
로프트에 테사랑 엄청
The woman who took Tessa,
Dia Nobile, she has a bedroom
닮은 아이의 방이 있더라구요
in her loft that's extremely
similar to Tessa's.
그리고 유모 말로는
그 여자를 들인 적이 없대요
And your nanny said
that she didn't let her in.
저희도 마찬가지에요
말씀 드렸었잖아요
Neither did we.
We told you that.
집을 내놓으신건 아니죠?
Your apartment's not for sale,
is it?
지난 봄에 내놓긴 했었어요
Well, it was on the market
last spring.
저희 브로커에게 확인해보세요
You can check with our broker.
그리고 테사를 낳았는데
She also said
that she gave birth to Tessa,
입양시켰다고 하더라구요
and that she gave her up
for adoption.
정신이 나간 여자네요
So she's a nut job.
근데 그 여자에게
여자아이 출생증명서가 있었는데
Well she does have a birth
certificate for a baby girl,
테사랑 같은 나이더군요
same age as Tessa.
- 하지만 테사가 아니에요
- 어머님이 갖고 계시니까 말이죠?
- But it's not Tessa's.
- Because you have that one?
복사본 하나만 주실 수 있을까요?
그냥 절차에요
Can we get a copy of that,
just for protocol?
어, 테사의 생물학적 어머니 맞으시죠?
Uh, you are
Tessa's biological mother?
테사는 대리모를 통해서 태어났어요
Tessa was born through
a surrogate.
- 브레이든의 정자를 썼죠
- 그게 무슨
- With Braydon's sperm.
- What difference does
차이인거죠?
왜 다른 사람이 신경쓰는거죠?
that make?
Why is that anyone's business?
알겠습니다
Okay.
개인적으로 대리모를 구하신건가요,
에이전시를 통해서 구하신건가요?
Was it through a private
surrogacy, or through an agency?
개인적으로요
Private.
저희 변호사가
생모를 찾았어요
Our lawyer found
the birth mother.
완벽한 여자였어요
에린인가?
She was a wonderful woman.
Erin?
수의사가 되려고 공부한다더군요
She was studying to be a vet.
저희는 대학 등록금을 내고
We helped her pay
her college bills,
- 우리를 도와준거죠
- 서류 작업을 했나요?
- and she helped us.
- So you have all the paperwork?
대리모 합의서랑,
입양 서류요?
Surrogacy agreement,
adoption papers?
네, 모두 되어 있어요
저희 서류 살펴보셔도 돼요
Yes, everything is in order.
We can scan you the papers.
테사는 저희 애에요
Tessa is ours.
그럼 조지는
테사를 낳은게 아니고
So Josie didn't give birth
to Tessa,
디아는 자기가
생모라고 주장하는군
and Dia says
she's the biological mother.
테사를 입양한 사람들에게
She swears
that she was tricked
사기를 당했다고 주장하고 있어요
into letting them adopt Tessa.
이 부부에 대해서 지금까지 보거나
And the Leddys swear
that they've never seen
들은 적이 없다고 하고 있고?
or heard of her before now?
- 정신 나간 소리 같은데
- 하지만 출생 증명서와
- She sounds delusional.
- But she did have a file
친권 포기서의
waiting for us with
a copy of the birth certificate
사본을 갖고 있었어요
and the termination
of her parental rights.
세인트룩크 병원에서
And St. Luke's confirms
Dia delivered
디아가 아빠가 없는 아이를 출산하고
"baby girl Nobile,"
no father listed,
같은 주에 테사가
태어났다고 확인해줬어요
the same week Tessa was born.
닉, 그 부부는
우리에게 비밀로 하는게 있어
Nick, I mean, the Leddys
did hold out on us.
테사는 대리모를 통해 태어났고
Tessa was born to a surrogate,
그 부부는 우리가 아이를 찾기 전까지
and the Leddys
didn't let us know that
말해주지 않았어요
until after we found her.
그럼 그 쪽 서류는 어떤데?
Okay,
well how's their paperwork?
뉴욕 주 출생 증명서에는
가정분만이라고 쓰여져 있고
Uh, New York state birth
certificate for a home birth,
엄마는 에린 머피로,
the mother listed
as an Erin Murphy,
아빠는 브레이든 레디로 되어있어요
두번째 출생 증명서에는
the father, Braydon Leddy.
A second birth certificate
조지 레디가
입양모로 나오고 있어요
listing Josie Leddy
as the adoptive mother.
또 에린 머피의 친권 포기서도 있구요
They also had the termination of
Erin Murphy's parental rights.
그리고 전 지금 이상한걸 발견했어요
And I just found
a big red flag.
디아의 입양 서류와
레디 부부의 대리모 합의서가
Dia's adoption papers and
the Leddys' surrogacy agreement
같은 변호사에 의해 쓰여졌어요
웬델 피니?
were drafted by the same lawyer?
Wendell Feeney?
피니 씨는 지금 어딨지?
Where is Mr. Feeney?
- F-e-e-n-e-y?
- 네
- Yeah.
팟처그에 있는
웬델 피니가 하나 있어
Finding one Wendell Feeney
out in Patchogue.
신체 상해 변호사에요
A personal injury lawyer.
반장님, 이 얘긴 해야겠어요
디아의 눈을 보고 있자면
Captain, I gotta tell you.
By the look in her eye,
이 아이와 분명 연결점이 있어요
Dia may have a connection
to this baby.
제가 눈을 봤을 때는
그냥 미친 것 같던데요
Well what I saw in her eye
was a whole lot of crazy.
좋아, 봐
우린 아이를 찾았고
All right, look.
We found the baby,
납치범은 구금됐으니
우리 일은 끝이야
the kidnapper's in custody,
we're done.
하지만 아직,
반장님, 제발요
But still,
Captain, come on.
이 남자는 조사해볼 가치가 있어요
It's worth tracking
this guy down.
신뢰할 만한 사람인지만
조사해보면 안되나요?
I mean, just to see
if he's on the up and up?
좋아, 변호사랑
대화 한번만 해보고
All right, one conversation
with the lawyer,
이 판에서 손 떼는거야
and then this moves
off our plate.
브랙스톤 & 골드스테인
피니 법률 사무소
롱 아일랜드 팟처그
10월 8일, 월요일
전화 주셨으면
좋았을텐데요
I could have saved
you the trip.
웬델은 한달 전에
패혈증으로 죽었어요
Wendell died from sepsis
a month ago.
고관절 치환 수술을 하러 갔다가
Went in for a hip replacement,
- 다신 돌아오지 못했죠
- 유감입니다
- never made it back.
- I'm so sorry.
그럼 당신이 법률 파트너인가요?
And you were his law partner?
30년 동안이요
30 years.
저희는 입양과 대리모 서류를 찾고 있어요,
You know, we're looking into
an adoption
둘다 일년 전 일이구요
and a surrogacy,
both about a year ago.
생모는 디아 노블레에요
The birth mother
was a Dia Nobile.
입양이요?
Adoption?
저희는 가족에 관련된--
We don't do family--
그 사람의 사인이 맞네요
말이 안되는데요
That is his signature.
It makes no sense.
웬델이 예외를 만들었을 가능성이 있을까요?
Is it possible that Wendell
made an exception?
누가 사인을 위조한걸거에요
Maybe someone pasted
his signature onto this.
웬델은 규칙대로 하는 사람이거든요
Wendell was always by the book.
노블레 씨는
의뢰인으로 등록 안되어 있어요
Ms. Nobile is not showing
as a client.
그렇군요
Okay.
조지와 브레이든 레디로
검색 해주시겠어요? L-e-d-d-y?
Can you check Josie
and Braydon Leddy, L-e-d-d-y?
그 분들도 안 계시는데요
Mm, not them either.
이름 하나만 더 확인해주시겠어요?
If you could just check
one more name?
대리모인 에린 머피요
A surrogate, Erin Murphy.
에린 머피는 있네요
근데 대리모 일로는 아니네요
Okay, Erin Murphy I've got.
But not for a surrogacy.
슈퍼마켓에서
미끄러져서 넘어졌대요
A slip and fall
in a supermarket.
에린 머피요?
저희가 메세지를 남겼었는데
Erin Murphy?
We've left messages with her,
- 돌아오는 연락은 없었어요
- 만나보신 적은 있어요?
- but she hasn't called us back.
- Did you ever meet her?
아뇨, 대학 수업 때문에
바쁘다고 했어요
No, she was very busy with
her college classes,
스카이프로 대화는 했어요
스카이프 : 인터넷 전화, 채팅 프로그램
but we skyped.
저희가 대학교로
형사를 두 명 보냈는데요
We sent two detectives
to her campus.
더이상 거기 다니지도 않고,
She's no longer
registered there,
새 주소를 남기지도 않았더군요
and she didn't leave
a forwarding address.
피니가 저희에게 다시 연락을 주면
Well, maybe when Feeney
calls us back
그 때 어딨는지 알게 되겠죠 뭐
we can find out where she is.
피니는 연락 다신 못할겁니다
한달 전에 돌아가셨어요
He won't be calling you back.
He died a month ago.
잠깐만요, 웬델 피니가 죽었다구요?
Wait, Wendell Feeney's dead?
저흰 몰랐어요
연락하고 지내진 않았거든요
Well, we didn't know.
We're not exactly in touch.
- 어떻게 만나게 된거죠?
- 사촌의 남편이에요
- How did you meet him?
- He's a cousin by marriage.
가족 모임에서 얘길 들었다고 했어요
He heard me talking
at our family reunion
제 불임에 대해서요
about my fertility issues.
- 도와주고 싶다고 했었죠
- 그냥 말씀해주세요
- He offered to help.
- Look, just tell us...
피니가 저희 서류를 망쳐놓은건가요?
Did Feeney screw up
the papers?
그냥 서류 문제보다
더 큰 문제일 수도 있어요
It could be more
than just papers.
DNA가 필요합니다
We're gonna need DNA from you.
제가 테사의 아빠가
아닐 수도 있단 말씀이신가요?
You're saying
I'm not Tessa's father?
DNA 테스트로
확인하는건 쉬워요
Look, it's easy
to confirm with a DNA test.
브레이든, 그냥.. 해
Braydon, just... do it.
그냥 빨리 해치우자, 제발
Make this go away, please.
그럼 DNA 검사 결과에
테사가 제 딸이 맞다고 나오면
So once the DNA
proves Tessa's mine,
다시 데려올 수 있는거죠, 그쵸?
I get her back, right?
만약 당신이 생모라고 한다 해도
Honey, even if she is
your biological child,
애를 그렇게 데려올 순 없는거에요
you can't just steal her.
질문이 좀 있는데요
I gotta ask you a question.
왜 아이를 포기한거죠?
Why'd you give her up?
제 애인인
테사의 아빠가
Well, my lover,
Tessa's father,
잠시 뿐일거라 했어요
몇 달만 있음 된다구요
said it would only be temporary,
just a few months.
아내가 죽어가고 있었어요
His wife's dying.
뇌종양이 있었거든요
She has a brain tumor.
하지만 그 동안
몇달이 일년이 되고
But, meanwhile, a few months
turns into a year,
전 아이의 첫 걸음마도
생일도 놓쳤어요
and I miss her first steps,
her first birthday.
너무 했어요
It was just too much.
애 아빠와 얘기하고 싶어요
We're gonna need
to talk to the father.
디아, 내일 보석 심리가 있어요
Dia, you've got
a bail hearing tomorrow.
그 이야기를 확인시켜줄
사람이 필요해요
You're gonna need someone
to confirm your story.
그럴 수 없어요
애인이 화낼거에요
I can't.
I mean, he'd be furious.
만약 애 아빠랑 우리가 얘기할 수 없으면
Well, honey,
if we can't talk to him,
테사를 다시 볼 수 없을거에요
you're not gonna see Tessa.
켄트 웹스터엔디
존 아담스 로스쿨의 학과장이에요
It's Kent Webster, the dean
at John Adams Law School.
나이 많은 판사랑 가족 아닌가요?
He's related
to that old judge, right?
네, 클락 판사가 그 사람의 아빠에요
Yeah, Clark's his dad.
부전자전이죠
And the apple doesn't fall
far from the tree.
클락은 기품이 있지만
켄트는 화려하죠
Clark's distinguished,
but Kent is gorgeous.
대학 남동창회 매거진 커버 사진을
찍을 때 만났어요
We met when I shot the cover
photo for his alum magazine.
보자마자 욕망이 끓었죠
It was lust at first sight.
디아 노블레가 보석을 했대
Dia Nobile made bail.
프리랜서로 활동하면서
돈을 많이 벌었다는군
She has a healthy bank account
for a freelancer.
익명의 동업자가 있을 수도 있잖아요
Well, she might have
a silent partner.
테사의 아빠가
켄트 웹스터라고 주장하고 있어요
She's claiming that Tessa's
father is Kent Webster.
켄트 웹스터?
Kent Webster?
켄트는 대법원의
선발 후보자 명단 사람이고
He's on the short list
for the Supreme Court,
여자는 전에 요가강사를 했어
she's a former yoga instructor.
그 두 사람에게 접점이 어디있다고?
On what planet
do these two cross paths?
사진 촬영하다가 만났대요
They met on a photo shoot.
여자를 자른 에디터는
The editor who fired her
그 여자에 반(反)해서
보호명령을 받았더군요
still has an order of
protection out against her.
좀 불안정한 사람이긴 하죠
하지만 많은 남자들이 드라마를 좋아하잖아요
Okay, I mean, she's unstable.
But a lot of guys like drama.
긴급 속보에요
Breaking news.
레디 부부의 서류와
디아의 입양 서류
The Leddys' documents,
Dia's adoption papers,
모두 가짜에요
all fakes.
법원에는 없어요
They were never filed
with the court.
그럼 노블레의 아이로 등록된
출생 증명서만이
So baby girl Nobile's
birth certificate
합법적인 서류라는건가?
is the only
legitimate document?
모든게 다 사기라고?
Everything else
is part of a scam?
피니는 레디 부부의 사촌이야
이 일에 관여되어있는건가?
Feeney was the Leddys' cousin.
Are they in on this?
브레이든 레디는 온 마음을 다해
Braydon Leddy believes
with all his heart
자신이 아빠라고 믿고 있던데요
he's that little girl's
father.
DNA 테스트 결과가 나오기 전까진
저흰 손가락질 할 수 없어요
Well, until the DNA comes
back, we can't point fingers.
저희는 못하죠
하지만 디아는 했잖아요, 안그래요?
Well, we can't,
but Dia has, right?
켄트 웹스터에게요
At Kent Webster.
신중을 기해
벤슨, 같이 가
Tread carefully.
Benson, go with.
로스쿨로 찾아가
집으로 찾아가지말고
And at the school,
not his home.
존 아담스 로스쿨
워싱턴 플레이스 12번지
10월 9일, 화요일
디아 노블레
Dia Nobile.
전 많은 사람을 만나요
I meet a lot of people.
졸업생 잡지 때문에
당신 사진을 찍었다던데요
Well, she photographed you
for Alumni Magazine.
아, 맞아요, 맞아요
왜 물으시는거죠?
Oh, yeah, right, right.
Why are you asking me?
디아가 한살된 아이의 아빠가
Well, she says
you're the father
당신이라고 했는데
of her one-year-old daughter,
다른 가족들에 의해서 아이를
포기하라는 강요를 받았다고 하는군요
and that you forced her to give
the baby up to another family.
전 그 여자 알지도 못해요
I hardly know this woman.
그럼 아이 아빠가 아니신가요?
So you're not her baby daddy?
당연히 아니죠
거의 알지도 못하는데
Absolutely not.
I barely know her.
디아는 당신을 알던데요
She knows you.
당신 경력에 대한
개인적인 세부사항도 다 알고
She knows personal details
about your career,
- 당신 아내의 병도 알던데요
- 제 아버지가 판사세요
- your wife's illness.
- My father's a judge.
아버지 자서전이 올해 나왔었어요
His autobiography
came out this year.
저희의 삶이 말그대로
책으로 나와 있어요
Our lives are literally
an open book right now.
잠시만요, 딘 웹스터 씨?
Excuse me, Dean Webster?
잠시만요, 무슨 일이죠?
Give me a second?
Yeah?
디아 노블레가 전화 했어요
A Dia Nobile called.
집에서 만나자고 하시던데요?
She said she'll meet you
at home?
그이를 놓아주세요!
You need to let him go!
- 테사를 저와 키우고 싶어 했어요
- 켄트, 이 사람 누구에요?
- He wants to raise tessa with me.
- Kent! Who is this?
- 자기, 올 줄 알았어
- 정신 나갔어요?
- Baby, I knew you'd come.
- Are you out of your mind?
떨어져
- Come--
- Get--get away.
- 디아, 물러서요
- 떨어져!
- Dia, step back.
- Get away!
디아, 물러서요!
Dia, step back!
이 미친 여자를
제 집에서 끌어내세요
Get this crazy woman
off my property.
가자, 가자
Go, come on.
켄트?
Kent?
집으로 들어가자
가자
Get in the house.
Come on.
가자
전 스토커가 아니에요
켄트는 절 사랑해요
I'm not a stalker.
Ken loves me.
그걸 참 웃기게도 증명하더군요
He's got a funny way
of showing it.
켄트는 그래야만 했어요
부인이 바로 옆에 있었잖아요
Well, he had to.
She was right there.
문자를 보세요
제 핸드폰이 가방에 있어요
Look at his text.
My phone's in my bag.
"당신은 내 은하계에서
유일한 별이야"
"You're the only star
in my galaxy,"
"내가 가장 행복한 장소는
당신의 골든 트라이앵글이야"
골든 트라이앵글 : 세계적인 헤로인 생산지
"my happiest place
is in your golden triangle."
그게 제가 제일 좋아하는거에요
That's my favorite one.
이걸 자기 폰으로 보냈다구요?
And he sent these
from his cell?
아뇨, 저흰 전용 핸드폰이 있어요
No, we have a private phone.
그럼 그 사람 핸드폰이라고
증명할 길이 없네요
So there's no way
to prove they're from him.
킹 세바스찬의 사진도 보낸걸요
Yeah, but, he sent me pics
of King Sebastian.
우리가 그걸 그렇게 불러요
That's what we call it.
알겠어요
Okay.
정말 맹세컨데
테사는 켄트의 딸이에요
Look, I swear,
Tess is Kent's.
하지만, 어, 전--
But, uh, I--
제가 켄트를 할퀴었어요
여기서 DNA 채취하시면 안돼요?
I scratched him.
Can you get DNA from that?
- CSU 여기 불러주시겠어요
- 네, 갈게요
- Hey, get CSU over here.
- Yeah, right away.
아이를 납치했다구요?
She kidnapped a baby?
- 왜- 왜 보석을 내준거죠?
- 연락하신 적 있으세요?
- Wh--why is she out on bail?
- Have you had contact with her?
아뇨, 전--
No. I mean, I--
사진 찍어줘서 고맙다고
일년 전에 전화한 적은 있어요
I called her a year ago
to thank her for the photos.
그 이후로 저희 집에 좀 많이 전화했었고
She called me back on my home
phone a few too many times,
느낌이 좀 이상해서
전화번호를 바꿨어요
and my radar was up,
and I changed the number.
문자 보내신 적이 없단거죠?
So you never sent her
any texts?
그렇게 말하던가요?
Is that what she said?
사진은요?
How about pictures?
- 얼굴 사진 얘기하는거 아니에요
- 미친 여자군요
- And I don't mean of your face.
- She's nuts.
제 핸드폰 확인해보세요
한번 보세요
You can check my phone.
See for yourself.
누가 봐도 말을 꾸며낸거에요
She's obviously
making the whole thing up.
제가-- 제가 할게요
I'll--I'll get that.
그 전에 디아 얘기를 한 적이 있나요?
Has Kent mentioned
Dia before?
아뇨, 남편은 그 여자를 몰라요
No. No, he doesn't know her.
한나, 넌 들어본 적 있니?
Hannah, had you heard of her?
- 당연히 아니죠
- 엄마?
- Of course not.
- Mom?
걔는 나랑 줌바 수업을 듣는데
줌바 : 피트니스의 한 종류
Eh, she's in my zumba class,
저랑 몇 번 따로 만났어요
and I went out with her
a few times.
죄송해요
전 몰랐어요
I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
말을 하면 안됐던거에요
I never would have talked
to her.
한나, 당신은 몰랐잖아요
Hannah,
you couldn't have known.
형사님이 맞아, 아가
She's right, sweetheart.
그 여잔 미친거야
The woman is crazy.
한나, 잠깐 따로 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까요?
Hannah, why don't you come
talk to me for a second?
커피 두세번 같이 마셨어요
We had coffee
two or three times.
그리고 나니까 저희 아빠를
알고 있다고 하더라구요
And then she told me
she knew my dad.
매력적이라면서,
근데 다들 그렇게 말해요
That he was charming,
but everybody says that.
- 엄마에 대해서 말도 하던가요?
- 정말 말도 안돼요
- She ever mention your mom?
- That's what's so messed up.
엄마에 대해서 많이 얘기했어요
I mean,
she talked about her a lot,
엄마 치료에 대해서 묻고,
제가 어떻게 견디는지에 대해서요
asking about her treatments
and how I'm holding up.
그래서 개인적인 사항을
빨리 알아낸거군요
So she got personal
pretty quickly.
저희 엄마가 아프신건
참 힘든 일이에요
It's been hard
with my mom sick.
제 언니가 되고 싶은 것처럼 느꼈어요
I felt like she wanted
to be my big sister.
결혼생활은 괜찮으신가요?
Your marriage is solid?
항상 완벽하진 않죠
Well, it hasn't always
been perfect.
하지만 제가 진단 받고 나서
켄트는 제 버팀목이 되어주고 있어요
But since my diagnosis,
Kent has been a rock.
그 여자를 떨어트려 놓을
Can't you get one of those
명령같은걸 얻어다줄 수는 없나요?
orders of selection
to keep her away?
- 보호 말하는거지, 여보
- 아
- You mean protection, honey.
- Oh.
괜찮아
It's okay.
제 증상 중 하나에요
단어가 뒤섞여요
It's my condition.
The words get scrambled.
- 괜찮습니다
- 저희가 보호 명령을 받아내면
- I understand.
- If we get an OOP,
언론에도 알려질거야
that's public.
집 밖에 기자들이 몰려들거야
그럴 필요는 없어
Reporters outside the house.
You don't need that.
그 미치광이에게 전해주세요
제 가족 근처에 오기라도 하면
You tell the nutcase, she comes
anywhere near my family,
고소할거라구요
we'll press charges.
오래 걸려서 미안해요
Sorry this took so long,
양육권 분쟁은 우리가
최우선으로 생각하는게 아니라서요
but custody disputes are not
a priority around here.
단순 양육권 분쟁보다는
더 복잡해질 것 같아요
Well, this could be
more complicated than that.
아직 모든 질문에
대답할 수 있는건 아니지만
I don't have
all the answers yet,
디아 노블레는
테사의 생모가 맞아요
but Dia Nobile
is Tessa's biological mother.
- DNA가 일치해요
- 그럼 아이에 대해선
- The DNA's a match.
- So she was telling
진실을 말했네요
아빠는 누구에요?
the truth about that.
Who's the father?
브레이든 레디는 아니에요
You can rule out
Braydon Leddy.
얘기하기가 껄끄러워지겠네요
That's gonna be a difficult
conversation to have.
켄트 웹스터는요?
And Kent Webster?
디아가 잘 할퀴어 놔서
She scratched him up
pretty good, and we have
DNA도 충분히 있지만...
more than enough DNA, but...
이 일이 최우선은 아니라서요
again, it's not at
the top of the work list.
좀 빨리 해주실 순 없을까요?
Is there any way
to hurry that up?
디아는 켄트가 자신들의 사랑의 결과를
'Cause Dia's claiming
that Kent tricked her
포기하게 사기를 쳤다고 주장하고 있거든요
into giving up
their love child.
그리고 레디부부는 테사가
And the Leddys were tricked
into believing
대리모를 통해 낳은
that baby Tessa
came to them
- 자신들의 아이라고 믿고 있어요
- 알고 계시겠지만
- through a surrogate.
- You do know,
켄트가 생부인 것이 밝혀지더라도
even if it turns out that Kent
is the biological father,
아이에 대해서 알고 있을거라는
증거가 되진 않아요
there's no way I can prove
he knew about the baby.
알고 있었을걸요
그러니까
Oh, he knew.
I mean, come on,
음란문자에, 추적불가능 폰에
정부를 임신시키고
the sexting, the burner cell.
He knocked up his mistress,
여자를 조용히 시키려고
가짜 법정서류를 만들어냈다구요
and then dummied up a bunch of
legal papers to keep her quiet.
소시오패스에요
He's a sociopath.
남자가 여자에게
일년 안에 해결된다고 했고,
He told her that
this would be resolved
여자는 그걸
깨우쳐주려고 하고 있어요
within a year, and now
she's trying to remind him.
켄트는 자신의 "킹" 사진을 보냈어요
You know, Kent did send her
photos of his "king."
확인할 방법이 없을까요?
Any way to verify?
비슷한 상태의
진짜를 보기 전까진 못해요
Not without seeing
the original in a similar state.
소환장 받을 수 있겠어요?
You want to ask
for that subpoena?
DNA 테스트는 언제 될까요?
How long for the DNA?
아이 아빠라고 확신해요?
You sure it's his?
그럼 한번 속여봐요
Bluff him.
제가 아빠라구요?
I'm the father?
말도 안돼요
That's not possible.
DNA는 거짓말을 하지 않아요
DNA doesn't lie.
신중하게 답변하시고 싶으실텐데요
You might want to carefully
consider your answer, Counselor.
좋아요
Okay.
가능성이 하나 있어요
There is one possibility.
저희가 판단하겠습니다
Yeah, we figured that.
사진을 찍고 나서
전 긴장이 됐어요
After the photo shoot,
I was, uh, tense.
디아가 제 어깨를 마사지 해줬죠
Dia massaged my shoulders.
방에는 저희 둘 뿐이였고
We were alone in the room,
전- 전 흥분됐어요
and I-I got aroused.
제 와이프는 아팠었고,
전--
My wife has been ill, and I--
이거 참 진짜 곤란하네요
This is
incredibly embarrassing.
계속하세요
Go on.
약해진 그 순간에
In a moment of weakness,
그 여자에게..
I let her give me...
긴장을 놔버렸어요
a manual release.
제가 아이의 아빠일 수가 없다고
You can see how
I didn't think that could
생각하는 이유에요
in any way father a child.
확실히 하자면,
Just to be clear,
you're saying that
디아가 당신의 정액을 훔쳐서
Dia retrieved your semen,
임신하는데 썼단 얘긴가요?
and then used it
to impregnate herself?
훔치는걸 보셨어요?
You see her do that?
아뇨, 그- 그게 끝나자마자
전 방을 떠났어요
No, I-I--when it was over,
I left the room.
즉- 즉시요
Imm--immediately.
이 일이 밖으로
You can appreciate
that this is not something
세어나가지 않았으면 감사하겠어요
that I want made public.
부인분도 몰랐으면 하시구요
Or your wife to find out.
그럼 질문 하나만 더 하죠
Okay.
So one more question, Counselor.
웬델 피니는 얼마나 잘 아십니까?
How well do you know
Wendell Feeney?
누군지 모르는데요
I don't think
I know who that is.
모르세요? 디아 아이의
No?
Well he faked
입양 서류를 꾸민 사람인데요
the adoption papers
for Dia's baby.
대리모 합의서를 꾸며내
He faked a surrogacy agreement
레디 부부에게 아이를 주었구요
to place the baby
with the Leddys.
전 아무 짓도 안했습니다
I had nothing
to do with this.
자신이 임신했다는 얘기도 안했어요
Dia didn't even tell me
she was pregnant.
클리닉에 샘플을 줬었단 말이에요
He gave the sample
at the clinic.
한번- 한번 확인해보세요
You can--
you can check the shipping.
테사는 브레이든의
창백한 피부랑 미소를 가졌어요
Tessa has Braydon's fair skin,
and his smile.
아이 사진을 보세요
이건 착오일거에요
Look at his baby pictures.
This is a mistake.
유감이에요
I'm sorry.
당신의 대리모인
에린 머피는
And your surrogate,
Erin Murphy?
테사를 낳은게 아니에요
디아 노블레가 낳았어요
She didn't give birth to Tessa.
Dia Nobile did.
세상에
Oh, my God.
아니에요, 잠시만요
No. Wait, wait.
피니가 이 모든걸
잡고 있다고 얘기했어요
Feeney told me
he handled everything.
테사는 우리 아이라구요
He told me Tessa
is our child.
- 우리 아이라구요
- 테사를 납치한 그 여자에게
- She is our child.
- Do you really think
우리 딸을 줘야 한다고 생각하세요?
they would give our daughter
to that woman who kidnapped her?
그건 법원의 몫입니다
That's up to the court.
보세요, 테사는 태어나자마자
당신들이 키웠어요
Look, you have raised Tessa
since birth.
제가 조언할 수 있는건
좋은 변호사를 얻으라는거에요
I advise getting the best lawyer
you can afford.
형사님들, 피니 씨가
사망한게 맞나요?
Detectives, I understand
Mr. Feeney is deceased?
맞습니다, 재판장님
Yes, Your Honor.
피니 씨의 회사에서
우릴 도와줄 사람이 있나요?
Can anyone in his firm
help us?
아뇨, 이 일은 기록되어있지 않습니다
No, these jobs
were off their books.
피니 씨의 집과 사무실을 수색했는데
서류의 흔적은 없었습니다
We searched his home and office.
There's no paper trail.
좋아요, 우리는 아이를
포기한 여성분이 계시는데
Okay.
We have a woman who gave up,
그 분이 자신의 아이를 납치한거죠
then kidnapped
her own biological daughter.
엉터리 서류를 가진
아이를 사랑하는 부모가 있구요
We have custodial parents
with fraudulent papers.
저희 의뢰인이 사기라는 것을
There's no evidence my clients
알았다는 증거가 없습니다, 재판장님
were aware of the fraud,
Your Honor.
이의있습니다!
그 변호사는 저 사람들의 사촌이였어요
Objection!
The lawyer was their cousin.
- 앉으세요, 노블레 씨
- 죄송합니다, 재판장님
- Sit down, Ms. Nobile.
- We're sorry, Your Honor,
하지만 웬델 피니는
레디 부부의 친척입니다
but Wendell Feeney
was related to the Leddys.
피니 씨는 노블레 씨에게 임시로
He deceived Ms. Nobile
아이를 맡기는거라고 믿게 만들었습니다
into believing they would
only have temporary custody.
저 사람들은 테사를 사서
대리모를 통해 낳은거라고
Yeah, they bought Tessa,
and tried to cover it up
사기치고 있는거에요
by pretending
to have a surrogate.
어떻게 감히 그런 말을!
No, how dare you!
이런--
저희는 사기당한거에요!
This--
We were lied to!
이 여자는
우리 아이를 납치했어요
This woman,
she kidnapped our child.
정숙하세요
Enough.
당신 모두들요
All of you.
노블레 씨, 피니 씨가
Ms. Nobile, whether or not
레디 부부와 공모했든 안했든
the Leddys were
in league with Mr. Feeney,
당신도 변호사로
피니 씨를 고용했어요
you also used Mr. Feeney
as your lawyer.
친권을 포기한다고 사인했어요
You signed away
your parental rights.
피니 씨를 어떻게 고용하게 된거죠?
How did you come
to hire Mr. Feeney?
아이 아빠의 사생활을
보호하라는 명령을 받아서
In order to protect
the privacy of the father,
- 대답할 수 없습니다, 재판장님
- 정말로 저걸
- I can't answer that, Your Honor.
- Are you really
허락하실 겁니까? 말도 안됩니다
just going to accept that?
That is ridiculous.
정숙하세요, 레디 씨
이건 어려운 결정입니다
Enough, Mr. Leddy.
This is a difficult decision.
테사를 정성과 애정으로
키우신걸 압니다
I know you've raised Tessa
with care and love.
저 사람들은 맞벌이에요!
They both work!
공원에서 아이를 쳐다보지도 않았다구요!
They weren't even watching her
in the park.
이젠 경고로
끝나지 않습니다, 노블레 씨
I won't warn you again,
Ms. Nobile.
하지만 피니 씨가 당신의 친척이니
But given that Mr. Feeney was
a relative of yours,
당신에게 과실이 없다는 것을
확인할 수 있는 것이 필요합니다
I need further assurance that
you have no culpability.
최종 양육권 심리를 하기 전까지
In the meantime,
I'm signing a temporary order
테사 레디를 ACS에
ACS : American Citizen Service
that Tessa Leddy be remanded
to the ACS
임시로 보내도록 하겠습니다
pending a final custody hearing.
- 제발요, 제발, 안돼요
- 안돼요, 우리 애에요
- Please, please, no.
- No. She's ours.
- 내 애라구요!
- 넌 미친년이야!
- She is mine!
- You're a crazy bitch!
브레이든, 판사 앞에서 이러지 마세요
Braydon, not in front
of the judge.
죄송합니다, ACS 사무관님에게
I'm sorry, I'll have
to ask the ACS officer
- 양육권을 임시로 넘기겠습니다
- 안돼-- 지금요?
- to take custody.
- No--now?
- 안돼, 안돼
- 제발, 제발 이러지 마세요
- No, no, no.
- Please, please don't do this.
- 조지, 조지, 조지
- 제발 이러지 마세요
- Josie, Josie, Josie.
- Please, no, you can't.
- 괜찮아, 봐, 조지
- 아이를 데려가지 마세요
- It's okay, look, Josie.
- You can't just take her away.
제발, 아이를 데려가지 마세요
이러지 마세요, 제발요
Please, don't take her from me.
You can't do this, please.
괜찮아, 아가
It's okay, baby.
이젠 어쩌죠?
이제 우리 어쩌죠?
Now what?
Now what do we do?
사기에 연루된게 아니라는 것을
증명하셔야 돼요
You prove that you weren't
complicit in the fraud.
어떻게요? 어떻게 피니가 우리에게
거짓말 했다는 것을 증명하죠?
How? How do we prove
that Feeney lied to us?
피니가 켄트 웹스터에 대해서
말한 적이 있나요?
Did Feeney ever mention
Kent Webster?
아뇨, 없어요
No, never.
서류에서 그 이름을 본 적은요?
You ever see his name
on paperwork?
파일에 표기 되었다거나
Maybe a notation in the file?
전화하면서 들었다거나?
Overhear a phone call?
피니의 사무실에서
테사를 데리러 갔던 일요일에
The Sunday that we picked
Tessa up from Feeney's office,
누구에게 전화하긴 했어요
he did call someone.
맞아요, 길지 않았어요
그냥 "끝났어요, 재판장님"이라고 하더군요
Right, it was quick.
Just, "It's done, Your Honor."
"재판장님"
"Your Honor."
체즈 듀말
듀언 가 136번지
10월 10일, 수요일
형사님들, 기다려줄 수 없으신가요?
Detectives, can't this wait?
- 저희 기념일인데요
- 아뇨, 못 기다려요
- It's our anniversary.
- No, it can't.
웬델 피니에 대해
몇가지 질문이 있습니다
We need to ask you some
questions about Wendell Feeney.
이미 말씀드렸잖아요
전 몰라요
I already told you,
I don't know him.
아마두요, 아버지인
클락 웹스터 판사가
Maybe.
Did you know your father,
피니를 알았다는 걸 아시나요?
Judge Clark Webster,
knew Feeney?
- 뭐라구요?
- 그대로에요
- Excuse me?
- Yeah.
레디 부부가 피니에게서
테사를 데려오던 날 밤
The night that the Leddys
picked up Tessa from Feeney,
판사에게 전화를 했더군요
he made a call to the judge.
그래서 저희가 확인해보니
Yeah, we did some checking.
피니가 로스쿨을 졸업한 그 해에
It turns out Feeney's
first year out of law school,
중범죄로 기소되어
변호사 자격이 박탈될 뻔 했는데
he was up on a felony charge,
facing disbarment.
당신 아버지가
판결을 파기했더군요
And your father vacated
the judgment.
피니의 경력을 살린거죠
Saved Feeney's career.
피니의 실수를
당신 아버지가 치웠어요
Your father cleaned up
Feeney's mess.
30년 후에
당신의 실수를 치운거죠
And 30 years later,
he's cleaning up yours.
노블레 씨가
그런 환상에 대해서 말하던가요?
Did Ms. Nobile tell you
this fantasy?
저희 아버지한테 물으세요
Feel free to ask my father.
그럴 예정입니다
선서 아래서 말이죠
Oh, we intend to.
Under oath.
좋은 밤 되세요, 형사님들
Good night, detectives.
저희 저녁을 망치고 계시니
Now that you've ruined
our dinner,
자리 좀 피해주실래요?
can you leave us in peace?
- 아빠?
- 왜그러니, 딸?
- Daddy?
- What honey?
- 이게 거짓말이라고 말하세요
- 뭔데?
- Tell me this can't be true.
- What?
오늘 같이 있었어요?
키스까지 하고?
You were with her today?
Kissing her?
딸아, 그냥 이거--
나한테 주렴, 이걸--
Okay, honey, let me just--
here, let me just--yeah--
- 무슨 일이야?
- 딸아, 안돼
- What's going on?
- Honey, no--
- 나한테서 떨어져요!
- 뭔데?
- Get off me!
- What?
이거- 이거 오늘이잖아
Th--this is from today.
- 이게 한번뿐인 실수야?
- 질리안...
- This is your one-time mistake?
- Gillian...
여기선 안돼, 알겠지?
설명할 수 있어
Not here, okay?
I can explain.
이 나쁜 자식
어떻게 이럴 수가 있어?
You bastard.
How could you?
보이는 거랑 달라
This is not
what it looks like.
- 보이는게 전부야
- 여보, 여보--
- This is exactly how it looks.
- Honey, honey--
이게 그 창녀가
우리집에 온 이유였어?
Oh, that's why that whore
came to our house?
여태까지 그 여자랑 뒹굴었어?
You were screwing her
this whole time?
우리 집에서 뒹굴었냐고
You were screwing her
in our house
- 내가 병원에 있을 때!
- 웹스터 씨
- when I was in the hospital!
- Ms. Webster.
웹스터 씨, 제발요
Ms. Webster, please.
그 여자랑 애가 있어!
You had a baby with her!
이 사진을 어떻게 얻었는지 알게 됐어요
Now we know
how they got these pictures.
디아가 스스로 파파라찌를 끌여들였어요
Dia called the paparazzi
on herself.
LMZ에 익명으로 어떤 여자가
켄트 웹스터가
Ugh, LMZ got an anonymous tip
from a female saying
호텔에서 정부를 만난다고 말했었나봐요
that Kent Webster was meeting
his mistress at a hotel.
디아가 기념일을 기념하러
나간다는 것을 알고
Dia knew that he was going out
for his anniversary,
벌을 주고 싶었던 거군
so she wanted to punish him.
하지만 이것들은 켄트가 테사에 대해
But none of this proves
Kent set up
사기를 알선했다고
증명되지가 않아
the fraudulent placement
of Tessa.
만약 켄트가 그런게 아니면
그 아버지가 그랬겠죠
Well, if he didn't do it,
his father did.
판사랑 언제 얘기를 할 수 있죠?
When do we get to talk
to the judge?
이미 늦었어
한시간 전에
Well, it's too late.
An hour ago,
존경하는 클락 웹스터 판사가
검사의 사무실로 가서
the esteemed Judge Clark Webster
went into the DA's office
자신의 동료에게 선서를 하고
거짓말을 했어
and lied under oath
to his associates.
피니와 10년이 넘게
얘기한 적이 없다고 맹세했다더군
He swore that he hadn't spoken
to Feeney in over a decade.
- 그리고 그걸 믿구요?
- 지역 관할구에서 디아의 로프트에
- And they believed him?
- A local precinct just got
가택 침입이 있었다고
신고가 들어왔대요
a report of a domestic
disturbance at Dia's loft.
우리가 가募鳴 얘기해
Tell them we'll handle it.
등을 보여
손을 보이게 들어
Turn around.
Let me see your hands.
형사님들, 디아가--
디아가 살해당했어요
Detectives, Dia--
Dia's been murdered.
내가 볼 수 있게 손을 들어!
Get your hands up where
I can see them!
제가 그랬다고 생각하시는거 아니죠
You can't think
that I did this.
그렇게 생각하는데
손을 들어!
Yes, we can.
Get your hands up!
손 들라고!
Get 'em up!
다시 말씀드리지만, 제가 갔을 땐
그 여자는 이미 죽어있었어요
Again, she was dead
when I got there.
"그 여자"?
연인을 말하는거겠죠, 디아요
"She"?
You mean your lover, Dia.
몇 시에요?
What time?
형사님들 오기 전
한 오분 전이였을겁니다
Maybe five minutes
before you arrived.
거기서 뭐하고 있었는데요?
What were you doing there?
절 괴롭히는데 화가 나있었어요
I was upset
about her harassment.
- 얘기하려고 갔습니다
- 그럼 대화를 할 수 없는
- I went to talk to her.
- Well, when you saw that she
상태인 것을 보았을 때는
wasn't really holding up
her end of the conversation,
왜 경찰에 신고하지 않았죠?
why didn't you
call the police?
- 그러려고 했습니다
- 그래서 디아의 서랍장에서
- I was about to.
- So it must've been your phone
핸드폰이라도 찾고 계셨나봐요
that you were looking for
in her desk drawer.
되찾아야 하는
개인적인 물건이 있었어요
Personal items
I wanted to retrieve.
디아가 피흘리고 있었는데
뭐가 더 중요하셨는데요?
While she was bleeding out.
What could be so important?
섹스 테이프요
Sex tapes.
디아가 전화해서
그걸 유출하겠다 했어요
Dia called and said
she would leak them.
저야 더이상 상처받지 않겠지만
한나는, 전- 전..
He can't hurt me anymore,
but for Hannah, I-I...
켄트에게 전화하라 해서
마음을 돌려보라고 했어요
I begged Kent to call her,
get her to change her mind.
디아가 전화한게 몇시죠?
What time did Dia call?
3시에요
지간을 확인하지 않았어요
3:00.
I didn't check the block.
- 시간! 시간이요
- 알겠습니다
- Clock! Clock.
- Okay.
켄트가 디아와 얘기하겠다고 했나요?
And Kent agreed
to talk to Dia?
그렇게 화내는걸 본 적이 없었어요
I have never heard him
so angry.
디아가 3시에 전화했다고
질리안이 말하던가요?
Gillian said Dia called
the house at 3:00?
헷갈린거에요, 종양이 있잖아요
6시였어요
She's confused, the tumor.
It was 6:00.
- 확신하세요?
- 네, 전 제 클럽에 있었어요
- You sure?
- Yeah, I was in my club,
라커 룸에요
지역 뉴스가 나오고 있었구요
locker room.
Local news came on.
근데 말이죠?
'Cause the thing is,
Counselor?
디아가 당신의 집으로 3시에 전화해서
We have
a five minute phone call
5분동안 통화한 기록이 있어요
from Dia's landline
to yours at 3:00 PM.
전 그 때 사무실에 있었어요
I was still in my office.
들어보세요..
Listen...
제 아내가 6시에 전화했어요
My wife called me
at 6:00.
디아가 섹스 테이프를 유출하겠다고
She told me that Dia
was threatening
협박했다고 하더군요
to release a sex tape.
당신 핸드폰 좀 봅시다
Let me see your cell phone.
제가 갔을 때 이미 죽어있었어요
She was dead when I got there.
누가 절 함정에 빠트린거라구요
Someone set me up.
진짜요? 누가요?
Seriously? Who?
몰라요
I don't know.
제 아내와 이야기 하고 싶어요
I need to talk to my wife.
자기 폰으로 전화했을 수도 있어
Could have called
his own cell.
아님 아내가 전화하기까지
3시간정도 시간이 있었어
Or his wife waited
three hours to call.
충분한 시간이야
It gives her enough time.
여자는 굉장히 아파
너라면 무슨 말을 하겠어?
The woman is gravely ill.
What are you saying?
아내에게 돌아가보죠
Just that we should
go back to her.
가보기 전에
켄트의 알리바이를 확인하고
Before you do,
check his alibi,
워너에게 시간대를 알려달라 해
and see where Warner is
on the timeline.
치유 수정에는
지문이 없었지만
I couldn't lift any prints
off the healing crystal,
그게 살인 도구는 맞아요
but it is the murder weapon.
10kg에
몇번이나 강타했어요
20 pounds, multiple blows.
둔기에 의한 외상이
두개골 골절을 일으켰어요
Blunt force trauma with
depressed skull fractures.
시간은 추정할 수 있어요?
Can you pin down a time?
저녁 8시에 직장 온도가
섭씨 34도 정도였으니
Rectal temperature
at 8:00 PM was 94 degrees,
3시에서 5시 사이에요
so sometime between
3:00 and 5:00.
- 6시가 아니구요?
- 이런 날씨에요?
- Not 6:00?
- Warm day?
시체는 그렇게 빠르게 차가워지지 않아요
Body wouldn't have cooled
that fast.
켄트의 알리바이는 확인됐어
Kent's alibi checked out.
캠퍼스 경비가 4시까지
사무실에 있는걸 봤대
Campus security puts him
in his office till 4:00.
클럽에서는 5시에서 6시 사이에
있었다는 것을 확인해줬고
Club confirms he was there
from 5:00 to 6:00.
그걸로 완벽하게 커버는 안돼
Well, it does give him
a little window.
그럼 4시 30분에 디아를 죽이고
What, so he kills her at 4:30
2시간 후에 사건 현장에
다시 돌아왔단 말씀이세요?
and comes back to
the crime scene two hours later?
그거보단 더 똑똑한 것 같던데
I'd like to think
he's smarter than that.
똑똑할걸요
Well, maybe he is.
911에 전화한 사람의
오디오 파일이 있는데
I got an audio file
of the 911 call?
공중전화였고, 익명이였어요
6시 10분에 전화가 왔구요
Anonymous, from a payphone,
at 6:10.
- 제가 미친거 아니겠죠
- 반담 245번지 꼭대기층에서
- Tell me if I'm crazy.
- Screams coming from
비명이 들렸어요
245 Vandam, top floor.
- 제 생각에 누가 재친거 같아요
- 부인?
- I-I think someone's being skirt.
- Ma'am?
어, 해친거 같아요
누가 해친거 같아요
Uh, yes, hurt.
I think someone's being hurt.
익명이 아닌데
Not so anonymous.
들렸어요
Top floor.
- 제 생각에 누가 재친거 같아요
- 부인?
- I-I think someone's being skirt.
- Ma'am?
어, 해친거 같아요
누가 해친거--
- Uh, yes, hurt.
I think someone's being--
음성 분석을 할 수도 있겠지만
이건 당신이에요
- We can have a voice analysis
done, but that's you,
그렇죠, 웹스터 씨?
isn't it Mrs. Webster?
웹스터 씨?
Mrs. Webster?
웹스터 씨, 괜찮으세요?
웹스터 씨!
Mrs. Webster, are you all right?
Mrs. Webster!
앰뷸런스 좀 불러주세요!
Hey, we need an ambulance!
의사 말로는
부분 발작을 일으킨건데
So the doctor says
she had a focal seizure,
뇌종양엔 흔한 거래
which is common
for her kind of brain tumor.
얘기해볼 순 있는데
오래는 못한다는군
He said we can talk to her,
but not for long.
- 웹스터 씨
- 그렇게 부르지 마세요
- Mrs. Webster.
- Don't call me that, please.
알겠습니다
Okay.
기분만 좀 괜찮으시다면
아까 못 다한
Look, if you're feeling
up to it, we'd like to
이야기를 하고 싶은데요
continue the conversation.
- 딸아, 쥬스 좀 가져다 줄래
- 잠시만, 한나
- Oh, honey, get me some juice.
- Hold up a second, Hannah.
어제 학교 끝나고
뭐 했는지 얘기 해줄래?
Um, can you tell us where you
went yesterday after school?
- 집에 왔어요
- 절 돌보러 왔죠
- I came home.
- To take care of me.
오후 내내?
All afternoon?
- 네
- 너희 어머니는?
- Yes.
- Well, how about your mom?
- 오후 내내 엄마도 집에 계셨니?
- 엄마?
- Was she home all afternoon too?
- Mom?
대답할 필요 없단다
Yeah, you don't have to
answer that.
나가서 대기실에 가 있어
You go ahead out
into the waiting room.
가렴, 딸
Go, darling.
절 보호하려 하는거에요
She's trying to protect me.
아이에겐 공평치 못해요
It's--it's not fair to her.
무슨 뜻이시죠?
How do you mean?
디아가 어제 3시에 전화를 했어요
Dia did call me
at 3:00 yesterday.
섹스 테이프에 대해서 얘기하려구요
To tell you
about the sex tape.
좋아하더군요
그 여잔--
To gloat.
She--
제가 얘기를 하고 싶다고 했어요
I told her that I-I wanted
to talk to her.
자기 집으로 오라더군요
She told me
to come to her place.
설득할 수 있다고 생각하셨나요?
And you thought
you could reason with her?
미친거 같죠, 알아요
절 미치게 만들더군요
Crazy, I know.
She's driven me crazy.
제가 거기 갔을 때
When I got there,
전, 전 우리 가족을
내버려달라고 해줬어요
I-I begged her
to leave my family alone.
제 얼굴을 보며 비웃더군요
She just laughed in my face.
그- 그 여잔 곧
켄트의 아내가 될 거고
She--she told me that soon
she would be Kent's wife,
한나의 새엄마가 될거라더군요
and Hannah's new mom.
전- 전 정신이 나가서
수정을 집어들고
And I-I just lost it.
I picked up the
그리고--
crystal, and I--
전 미안하지 않아요
I'm not sorry.
집에 와서
낮잠을 잤는데
I went home and I took a nap,
한나가 저녁 먹자고 깨우더군요
and... Hannah woke me
for dinner.
켄트에게 전화해서
로프트에 가보라고 했어요
I called Kent and I told him
to go to the loft.
그리고 911에 전화하셨군요
And then you called 911.
전 남편에게 화가 나 있었어요
I was so angry with him.
질리안, 분명히 당신은 남편에게
Gillian,
you certainly have reason
화가 날만한 이유가 있어요
to be angry with your husband.
하지만 저번에 봤었는데..
But I noticed the other day...
물병을 제대로 못 집으시더군요
that you couldn't pick up
the water pitcher.
제 파트너가
도와드렸잖아요?
I mean, my partner
had to do it for you, right?
좋을 때도 있고 나쁠 때도 있어요
Well, I have
good days and bad.
그 크리스탈,
살인 도구요
Well, the crystal,
the murder weapon,
얼마나 컸었죠?
how big was it?
그 물병보다 2배는 무거워요
Twice as heavy
as that pitcher.
- 분노가 힘을 실어줬어요
- 질리안..
- Anger gave me strength.
- Gillian...
저흰 한나가 상처받은걸 봤어요
We saw Hannah's hurt.
이 모든 일을 겪으며
아이는 당신 편이였어요
She's been by your side
through this whole thing.
따님이 디아에게 전화를 했나요?
Did she call you from Dia's?
아뇨, 아뇨 디아가 했어요
제가 말씀드렸잖아요
No. No, Dia did.
I told you that.
디아는 전화번호가 없어요
Dia didn't have
your home number.
켄트가 바꿨어요
Kent changed it.
자신을 위해서요, 기억나세요?
For his own sake, remember?
질리안..
Gillian...
한나가 디아랑 직면했다면,
If Hannah confronted Dia,
배심원단들은 따님의
감정적인 상태를 이해할거에요
a jury will understand
her emotional state.
그럴까요?
Would they?
배심원단은 15살 짜리 애가
A jury would understand
a 15-year-old
홈메이드 섹스 비디오를 보여주는 대신에
사과 받으려고 초대 되었고
being invited over there
for an apology,
그 사람들의 행위가 진실로
and instead being shown
a home-made sex video,
아름다웠다고 생각했다고
so she could understand
how truly beautiful
이해할걸요?
their lovemaking was?
하지만 이 일이
어떻게 흐르는건지만 알면--
But if that's how
this went down--
아뇨, 아니에요
그렇게 안될겁니다
No, no.
It didn't.
사람들은 항상 흥미거리를 얘기하죠
People always talk
about the joy.
사람들은 "딸의 첫키스, 결혼식을 놓친게
They say, "How sad it will be
that you'll miss her--
얼마나 슬프겠어"라고 말해요
her first kiss, her wedding."
하지만 부모가 진정으로 원하는 것은
What parents really want is...
아이를 보호하는거에요
to protect their child.
제가- 제가 빌게요
I'm--I'm begging you,
제발 제 아이를
보호할 수 있도록 해주세요
let me protect my child.
딸을 위해 해줄 수 있는
마지막 일이에요
It's the last thing
that I'll be able to do for her.
제발요
Please?
- 한나
- 엄마에게 쥬스를
- Hannah.
- I need to give
- 줘야 해요
- 잠깐 뭐 좀--
- my mom her juice.
- Just a couple things--
엄마는 절 필요로 하세요
She needs me.
죄송해요
I'm sorry.
질리안은 한나가
상담 받을거라고 확실히 해줬어
Gillian has made sure
that Hannah gets counseling.
모든 것에 대해서
For everything.
상담사가 나한테
바로 보고해주기로 했고
The counselor
is gonna report directly to me.
닉, 나 혼자서 할 수 있어
만약 무슨 의심이라도 된다면--
Nick, I can do this on my own.
If you have any doubts--
그래서
질리안이 자백했군
So... Gillian's confession.
그 무거운 수정을 들고서
She raised that heavy crystal
반복해서 디아의 머리를
내려 쳤다고?
and repeatedly struck
Dia's head?
아드레날린이 솟아오르는데
Mothers have been known
to lift a car
뭔들 못하겠어요
아이가 차에 깔렸을 때 엄마가 차를 들어올린 적이 있음
when their adrenaline's
pumping.
다른 용의자들은 제외하는거야?
Have we ruled out
other suspects?
딸은 어디 있었대?
Her daughter, where was she?
집에서 오후 내내 있었대요
Home, all afternoon,
locked in.
대법원 10호실
10월 15일, 월요일
질리안 웹스터...
Gillian Webster...
고의성이 없는
for the crime of
1급 살인에 대해서
어떻게 주장하시겠습니까?
manslaughter in the first
degree, how do you plead?
유죄입니다
Guilty.
관리원, 피고인을 구금하세요
Bailiff, take the defendant
into custody.
엄마, 안돼요!
Mommy, no!
쉬, 쉬
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
번역 by 내가아는카페 날로
blog.naver.com/narlo
Sync & corrections by Alex1969
www.addic7ed.com